Abraham: Let’s discuss the
possible motives for cyber crime.
The motives for cyber crime are
similar to those for crime in
general only they involve the
benefits of 'online anonymity'.
Cyber crime can be on more of a 'small'
scale where it can impact an individual
directly such as cyber bullying or phone
hacking or a small company that has
their whole computer system taken over.
This may be to gain control of their data,
holding them to ransom or adding malware.
However, it can also be on a large
scale where governments and large
organisations can be affected by
state sponsored attacks on their
security with world-wide repercussions.
The motivation for cyber criminals
can be wide-ranging, for example
those linked to ransomware, phishing,
internet and financial fraud, password
cracking, hacking and malware are
mainly motivated by financial gain but
can also be associated with pranks,
activism, cyber theft and espionage.
Cyber crimes against people such as cyber
stalking, bullying, trolling and revenge
pornography are likely to be motivated by
hatred or to intimidate or inflict harm.
Additionally, some cyber crime is
committed solely ‘because they can’!
Often criminals will hack a website or
computer just to prove to other hackers
that they can and to cause mayhem.
These are usually younger people
just getting into hacking with
spare time on their hands.
An example of this is the hacking
group LulzSec, who would often breach
news outlets like The Sun and The
Times and create fake news stories.